The true story of a mild mannered banker and his magnificent obsession.
Owning Mahowny is a crime, drama, thriller film
directed by Richard Kwietniowski.
Dan Mahowny was a rising star at the Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce.
At twenty-four he was assistant manager of a major branch in
the heart of Toronto's financial district.
To his colleagues he was a workaholic.
To his customers, he was astute, decisive and helpful.
To his friends, he was a quiet, but humorous man who
enjoyed watching sports on television.
To his girlfriend, he was shy but engaging.
None of them knew the other side of Dan Mahowny--the side that executed the largest single-handed bank fraud in
Canadian history, grossing over $10 million in eighteen months to feed his gambling obsession.
Dan Mahowny, played by Philip Seymour Hoffman.
Belinda, played by Minnie Driver.
Victor Foss, played by John Hurt.
Frank Perlin, played by Maury Chaykin.
Det. Ben Lock, played by Ian Tracey.
Bernie, played by K.C. Collins.
Owning Mahowny is a 2003 Canadian film starring Philip Seymour
Hoffman, Minnie Driver, Maury Chaykin and John Hurt.
The film is based on the true story of Brian Molony, a Toronto bank employee who
embezzled more than $10 million to feed his gambling addiction.
Owning Mahowny was named one of the ten best films
of the year by critic Roger Ebert.
The film explores themes of banker, casino, airport,
based on novel or book, gambling.
The tone is emotional and intense.